const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"A 55-year-old male presented to the clinic with the complaint of fever, weight loss, and back pain. On physical examination, extreme tenderness was noticed at the lumbar vertebrae. Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) of the lumbar spine showed evidence of Pott’s disease. Which of the following organisms is most commonly involved in this disease process?","answers":[{"option":"Mycobacterium tuberculosis","bool":true},{"option":"Salmonella species","bool":false},{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":false},{"option":"β-hemolytic streptococci","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudomonas aeruginosa","bool":false}]},{"id":1,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"A 45-year-old lady presented with sudden-onset of difficulty in micturition, and significant bilateral lower limb weakness. Examination reveals the power of 1/5 in both lower limbs, with saddle anesthesia. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Spondylolisthesis","bool":false},{"option":"Pott's disease","bool":false},{"option":"Spinal stenosis","bool":false},{"option":"Cauda equina syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Lumbar spondylosis","bool":false}]},{"id":2,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"Uric acid is the metabolic end product of which of the following compounds?","answers":[{"option":"Adenine","bool":true},{"option":"Thymidine","bool":false},{"option":"Cytosine","bool":false},{"option":"Uracil","bool":false},{"option":"Proteins","bool":false}]},{"id":3,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"Which of the following autoimmune diseases is associated with the highest rate of malignancy?","answers":[{"option":"Sjogren's syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Rheumatoid arthritis","bool":false},{"option":"Systemic lupus erythematosus","bool":false},{"option":"Dermatomyositis","bool":true},{"option":"Systemic sclerosis","bool":false}]},{"id":4,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"Twisting of bone along its long axis leads to which kind of fracture?","answers":[{"option":"Twist fracture","bool":false},{"option":"Oblique fracture","bool":false},{"option":"Spiral fracture","bool":true},{"option":"Greenstick fracture","bool":false},{"option":"Transverse fracture","bool":false}]},{"id":5,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"How is a Colle's fracture managed?","answers":[{"option":"Bone graft","bool":false},{"option":"Manipulation and casting","bool":true},{"option":"Intramedullary nailing","bool":false},{"option":"External fixation","bool":false},{"option":"Open reduction and internal fixation","bool":false}]},{"id":6,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"What are the effects of radiation in the eye?","answers":[{"option":"Conjuctivitis","bool":false},{"option":"Glaucoma","bool":false},{"option":"Keratitis","bool":false},{"option":"Cataract","bool":true},{"option":"Anterior uveitis","bool":false}]},{"id":7,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"A 40-year-old woman presents to the clinic with shortness of breath, nausea, and difficulty walking upstairs. She has been taking medication for rheumatoid arthritis for the past 8 months. Which drug is most likely responsible for her complaints?","answers":[{"option":"Omalizumab","bool":false},{"option":"Gold salts","bool":false},{"option":"Steroids","bool":false},{"option":"Methotrexate","bool":true},{"option":"Leflunomide","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"What of the following is referred to as a \"Gamekeeper’s thumb\"?","answers":[{"option":"Monteggia's fracture","bool":false},{"option":"Injury to ulnar collateral ligament","bool":true},{"option":"Bennett's fracture","bool":false},{"option":"Galeazzi's fracture","bool":false},{"option":"Fracture of the thumb phalanges","bool":false}]},{"id":9,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"Which of the following is a non-nitrogenous bisphosphonate?","answers":[{"option":"Ibandronate","bool":false},{"option":"Alendronate","bool":false},{"option":"Etidronate","bool":true},{"option":"Risedronate","bool":false},{"option":"Pamidronate","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"Which antibody is associated with interstitial lung disease in patients with polymyositis and dermatomyositis?","answers":[{"option":"Anti-nuclear antibody","bool":false},{"option":"Anti-P140","bool":false},{"option":"Anti-Mi2","bool":false},{"option":"Anti-Jo1","bool":true},{"option":"Anti-P155","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"A 40-year-old female patient presents with back pain and extreme weight loss. She was diagnosed with breast cancer 5 years ago but she denied chemotherapy or any other form of treatment. What will be the next best investigation?","answers":[{"option":"Ultrasound","bool":false},{"option":"Bone scan","bool":true},{"option":"Mammogram","bool":false},{"option":"Chest X-ray","bool":false},{"option":"Spinal MRI","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"A 16-year-old child comes with his parents to the outpatient department. The parents complain to the doctor that their child has a short stature and has not developed puberty yet. The doctor examines the child and concludes that the bone age is less than the chronological age and diagnoses the child with constitutional growth delay. The parents are worried about the final height of the child. What would be the best treatment for this child?","answers":[{"option":"Reassurance and counselling","bool":true},{"option":"No treatment and the final height is decreased.","bool":false},{"option":"Growth hormone injections","bool":false},{"option":"Low dose androgen therapy","bool":false},{"option":"Surgery to increase the height of femur","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"What is the best management for open fractures?","answers":[{"option":"Debridement + irrigation + antibiotic + stabilization","bool":true},{"option":"Internal fixation","bool":false},{"option":"Plating","bool":false},{"option":"Debridement + stabilization","bool":false},{"option":"Debridement","bool":false}]},{"id":14,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"A young gymnast comes to the outpatient department (OPD) with the complaint of lower back pain. The clinician after taking radiographs concluded that there is a defect in the pars interarticularis. What is this condition called?","answers":[{"option":"Bamboo spine","bool":false},{"option":"Psoriatic arthritis","bool":false},{"option":"Spondylolysis","bool":true},{"option":"Spondylolisthesis","bool":false},{"option":"Spine osteoarthritis","bool":false}]},{"id":15,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"A consultant confirms that there is a fracture of the pars interarticularis on the X-ray and is worried about it. What is the complication that this existing condition would lead to?","answers":[{"option":"Complete cord injury","bool":false},{"option":"Lumbar disc herniation","bool":false},{"option":"Spondylolisthesis","bool":true},{"option":"Cauda equina syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Spondylolysis","bool":false}]},{"id":16,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"A 30-year-old male comes to the outpatient department with a complaint of acute onset shoulder pain. On examination, the external rotation is possible and there is a sub-acromial calcification seen on a plain radiograph. What is the most probable diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Adhesive capsulitis","bool":false},{"option":"Calcific tendinitis","bool":true},{"option":"Frozen shoulder","bool":false},{"option":"Rheumatoid arthritis","bool":false},{"option":"Rotator cuff tear","bool":false}]},{"id":17,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"Which of the following cases produces \"light bulb\" sign on X-ray anteroposterior view?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior shoulder dislocation","bool":false},{"option":"Clavicular shaft fracture","bool":false},{"option":"Acromioclavicular fracture","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior shoulder dislocation","bool":true},{"option":"Proximal humerus fracture","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"Which of the following vertebrae is involved in Jefferson's fracture?","answers":[{"option":"C2","bool":false},{"option":"C3","bool":false},{"option":"C4","bool":false},{"option":"C1","bool":true},{"option":"C5","bool":false}]},{"id":19,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"A patient was prescribed hydralazine in order to control her hypertension. She later developed a malar rash, photosensitivity, and arthritis. What is the most likely diagnosis in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Sjogren","bool":false},{"option":"Systemic sclerosis","bool":false},{"option":"Rheumatoid arthritis","bool":false},{"option":"Drug-induced lupus","bool":true},{"option":"Systemic lupus erythematosus","bool":false}]},{"id":20,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"Which of the following gases is known to seep out from under houses and leak during construction/digging of earth, and potentially cause lung cancer?","answers":[{"option":"Radon","bool":true},{"option":"Hydrogen sulfide","bool":false},{"option":"Nitrous oxide","bool":false},{"option":"Carbon monoxide","bool":false},{"option":"Chloroform","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"A 9-year-old child is brought to the clinic with pain in the right leg associated with swelling. X-ray reveals evidence of Brodie's abscess. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Osteopenia","bool":false},{"option":"Osteomyelitis","bool":true},{"option":"Osteosarcoma","bool":false},{"option":"Arthritis","bool":false},{"option":"Rickets","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"A newborn is noticed to have the right upper limb missing from the forearm onward. Which term best describes this condition?","answers":[{"option":"Meromelia","bool":true},{"option":"Phocomelia","bool":false},{"option":"Rhizomelia","bool":false},{"option":"Micromelia","bool":false},{"option":"Amelia","bool":false}]},{"id":23,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"An intravenous drug user presents with the complaint of burning micturition and fever for 3 days. He also has gritty eyes and lower back pain for the past 3 months. He also has an ulcer on the glans of the penis. What is the most likely cause of these symptoms?","answers":[{"option":"Behcet's syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"HIV infection","bool":false},{"option":"Tertiary syphilis","bool":false},{"option":"N. Gonorrhea infection","bool":false},{"option":"Reiter's syndrome","bool":true}]},{"id":24,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"A child presents to the emergency department with a radius fracture. The surgeon wants to preserve the periosteum. What is the most likely reason for preserving the periosteum?","answers":[{"option":"It is osteogenic","bool":true},{"option":"It provides muscle attachment","bool":false},{"option":"It produces new cells","bool":false},{"option":"It provides attachment to tendons","bool":false},{"option":"It is protective","bool":false}]},{"id":25,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"A 45-year-old male patient presents to the clinic with a complaint of dull hip pain for 3 years. On investigation, there is a mass of 10 cm × 13 cm attached to the hips which has irregular borders. Removal of the mass from ischium for biopsy reveals spotty calcifications. The transverse section of the mass reveals a blue-gray color. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Enchondroma","bool":false},{"option":"Ewing sarcoma","bool":false},{"option":"Giant cell tumor","bool":false},{"option":"Chondrosarcoma","bool":true},{"option":"Osteosarcoma","bool":false}]},{"id":26,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"Which compound is responsible for the viscosity of synovial fluid?","answers":[{"option":"Hyaluronic acid","bool":true},{"option":"Prostaglandins","bool":false},{"option":"Lubricin","bool":false},{"option":"Heparan sulfate","bool":false},{"option":"Collagenases","bool":false}]},{"id":27,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"A 42-year-old female presents to the outpatient department with complaints of progressive pain in different joints of the body, including small joints of the hands and knee joint for 2 months. She also has morning stiffness for about one hour every day. On examination, she has swelling of small joints of the hands and mild anemia. Which of the following investigations is most helpful in establishing a diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Anti-citrullinated peptide antibodies","bool":true},{"option":"Rheumatoid factor","bool":false},{"option":"Antinuclear antibodies","bool":false},{"option":"Anti-smooth muscle antibodies","bool":false},{"option":"Extractable nuclear antigen","bool":false}]},{"id":28,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"A 17-year-old girl presents to the outpatient department with complaints of low-grade fever, oral ulcers, and pain in small joints of her hands for 6 months. She is also having decreased urination with frothy urine. On examination, she has patchy hair loss, bilateral pedal edema, and swollen joints. Which of the following investigations has the highest prognostic value?","answers":[{"option":"Increased protein creatinine ratio","bool":true},{"option":"Decreased albumin","bool":false},{"option":"Increased creatine","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased hemoglobin","bool":false},{"option":"Increased urea","bool":false}]},{"id":29,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"A 42-year-old male presents to the outpatient department with a complaint of low back pain for the past few years. He also has morning stiffness and pain which mostly stays for 2-3 hours. Currently, he has been experiencing pain in the back of his right ankle, however, there is no history of trauma. Which of the following is the most appropriate investigation to establish the diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Rheumatoid factor","bool":false},{"option":"Antinuclear antibodies","bool":false},{"option":"X-ray of lumbosacral joint","bool":false},{"option":"ESR and CRP","bool":false},{"option":"HLA B-27","bool":true}]},{"id":30,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"Which of the following radiographic findings is characteristic of rheumatoid arthritis?","answers":[{"option":"Joint space narrowing","bool":false},{"option":"Subchondral sclerosis","bool":false},{"option":"Erosions","bool":true},{"option":"Osteophytes","bool":false},{"option":"Soft tissue swelling","bool":false}]},{"id":31,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"A 67-year-old male, retired from his occupation, presents to the clinic with a complaint of non-radiating backache. He has lost 3 kg weight and his height is reduced by 3.5 cm. There is no comorbid, history of smoking or alcohol.  DEXA scan shows a T score of -2.3 at the femoral neck. What is the best treatment plan for this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Lifestyle modification, calcium and vitamin D supplements","bool":false},{"option":"NSAID group of drugs, calcium and vitamin D supplement","bool":false},{"option":"Bisphosphonate, lifestyle modification and calcium supplement","bool":false},{"option":"Bisphosphonate, lifestyle modification, calcium and vitamin D supplements","bool":true},{"option":"Bedrest physiotherapy and calcium supplement","bool":false}]},{"id":32,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"A 5-week-old male infant is brought to the clinic with a complaint of inward rotation of feet since birth. What is the best treatment option for this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Physiotherapy","bool":false},{"option":"Foot braces","bool":false},{"option":"Achilles tendon surgery","bool":false},{"option":"Serial casting","bool":true},{"option":"Reassurance","bool":false}]},{"id":33,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"On which of the following organs does the parathyroid hormone act directly to increase serum calcium levels?","answers":[{"option":"Bones and liver","bool":false},{"option":"Kidneys and bones","bool":true},{"option":"Lungs and spleen","bool":false},{"option":"Stomach and intestines","bool":false},{"option":"Liver and pancreas","bool":false}]},{"id":34,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"A 10-year-old boy is brought to the clinic with a complaint of on-and-off pain in the knee joint for the last six months. On examination, his weight is at the 90th percentile, and there is a painful waddling gait with externally rotated feet. An x-ray of the hip joint is advised. What will be the expected radiological findings?","answers":[{"option":"Flattening of head of femur","bool":false},{"option":"Inflammation at the knee joint","bool":false},{"option":"Patchy vascularity of head of femur","bool":false},{"option":"Widening of interarticular space at the knee joint","bool":false},{"option":"Melting cone appearance at head of femur","bool":true}]},{"id":35,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"Which of the following is the basis to confirm the diagnosis of gout?","answers":[{"option":"Increased uric acid excretion in urine","bool":false},{"option":"Renal stones","bool":false},{"option":"Joint pain and redness","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperuricemia","bool":false},{"option":"Urate crystals in synovial fluid","bool":true}]},{"id":36,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"Which of the following enzymes is used to convert hypoxanthine to xanthine and xanthine to uric acid?","answers":[{"option":"Phosphoribosyl pyrophosphate synthetase","bool":false},{"option":"Xanthine oxidase","bool":true},{"option":"Xanthine reductase","bool":false},{"option":"Adenosine deaminase","bool":false},{"option":"Hypoxanthine-guanine phospho-ribosyl-transferase","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"A 46-year-old man on dialysis due to chronic kidney disease presented to the physician for bilateral fractures of the tibia and fibula after falling in a washroom. He was treated with open reduction and internal fixation. His orthopedic surgeon ordered a dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry (DEXA), whose findings were consistent with the diagnosis of osteoporosis. Other investigations showed higher parathyroid hormone, low calcitriol, and low plasma calcium levels. Which of the following is the trigger for the aforementioned phenomenon?","answers":[{"option":"Reduced cholecalciferol activation","bool":true},{"option":"Excessive calcium excretion","bool":false},{"option":"Tumor of parathyroid gland","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased calcium intake","bool":false},{"option":"High plasma phosphate levels","bool":false}]},{"id":38,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"A 2-year-old child presents to the outpatient department with a complaint of inability to walk. The child's weight is 8 kg. He was breastfed only for 15 days then switched to formula milk with inadequate dilation. Weaning was started after 9 months and his current caloric intake is 55% of the total requirement. He achieved neck holding at 4 months, sitting at 8 months and currently, he can stand with support only. His first tooth erupted at the age of 14 months. What biochemical abnormalities are most likely in this child?","answers":[{"option":"Increased serum calcium, increased alkaline phosphatase","bool":false},{"option":"Increased serum calcium, increased parathyroid hormone","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased serum calcium, decreased alkaline phosphatase","bool":false},{"option":"Normal serum calcium, decreased parathyroid hormone","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased serum calcium, increased alkaline phosphatase","bool":true}]},{"id":39,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"For the evaluation of developmental dysplasia of the hip joint in a newborn, which of the following maneuvers is applied for assessment of dislocated hip joint?","answers":[{"option":"Murphy's maneuver","bool":false},{"option":"Trendelenburg's test","bool":false},{"option":"Ortolani test","bool":false},{"option":"Barlow test","bool":true},{"option":"Romberg's test","bool":false}]},{"id":40,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"A 2-year-old male child presents to the clinic with a complaint of short stature. On examination, he has a large head & tongue, corneal clouding, and coarse facial features. He is developmentally delayed. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Morquio Syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Gaucher disease","bool":false},{"option":"Hunter syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Hurler syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Hypothyroidism","bool":false}]},{"id":41,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"An 11-year-old boy presents to the outpatient department with complaints of fever, pain, and swelling in joints. The symptoms have been present for 10 days. Four days ago, his right knee was painful and swollen but it was resolved, and later, his right ankle and left knee joint were also involved. Previous history is positive for sore throat 4 weeks back which responded to symptomatic treatment. On examination, he is febrile, respiratory rate is 32/min and heart rate is 160/min. His left knee and right ankle joint are swollen and extremely tender and warm. There is a restricted range of motion. The routine investigation is as follows: CBC normal, ESR 110, and antistreptolysin O titer (ASOT) are 1:800. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Reactive arthritis","bool":false},{"option":"Rheumatoid arthritis","bool":false},{"option":"Tuberculous arthritis","bool":false},{"option":"Rheumatic fever","bool":true},{"option":"Septic arthritis","bool":false}]},{"id":42,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"A 21-year-old footballer comes to the clinic with a sudden onset, severe pain in his right groin after kicking a football. On examination, there is tenderness at the medial side of his thigh. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Quadriceps tendinopathy","bool":false},{"option":"Iliopsoas tendinopathy","bool":false},{"option":"Abductor tendinopathy","bool":false},{"option":"Adductor tendinopathy","bool":true},{"option":"Hamstring tendinopathy","bool":false}]},{"id":43,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"Which of the following is the serum marker for increased osteoblastic activity?","answers":[{"option":"C reactive protein","bool":false},{"option":"Bony alkaline phosphatase level","bool":true},{"option":"Total acid phosphatase level","bool":false},{"option":"Total alkaline phosphatase level","bool":false},{"option":"Bony acid phosphatase level","bool":false}]},{"id":44,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"Which of the following structures is commonly associated with the term \"strain,\" referring to an injury?","answers":[{"option":"Muscle","bool":true},{"option":"Soft tissue","bool":false},{"option":"Tendon","bool":false},{"option":"Nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Ligament","bool":false}]},{"id":45,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"What is the primary cause of an avulsion fracture?","answers":[{"option":"Muscle belly contraction","bool":false},{"option":"Artery force","bool":false},{"option":"Nerve at origin tension","bool":false},{"option":"Tendon pull","bool":true},{"option":"Vein traction","bool":false}]},{"id":46,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"A 30-year-old tennis player leaves the match in between due to a sudden onset of severe pain in the medial side of the thigh. On examination, there is a contusion in the middle of the medial side of the thigh. What is the diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Quadriceps tendinopathy","bool":false},{"option":"Iliopsoas tendinopathy","bool":false},{"option":"Hamstring tendinopathy","bool":false},{"option":"Abductor tendinopathy","bool":false},{"option":"Adductor tendinopathy","bool":true}]},{"id":47,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"A 25-year-old cricketer comes to the clinic with a complaint of pain in the back of the thigh. While bowling, he fell due to severe pain during the match. What is the most likely injured compartment?","answers":[{"option":"Adductor","bool":false},{"option":"Iliopsoas","bool":false},{"option":"Hamstring","bool":true},{"option":"Quadriceps","bool":false},{"option":"Abductor","bool":false}]},{"id":48,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"Which structure's contraction is responsible for causing snapping hip syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"Quadriceps","bool":false},{"option":"Sartorius","bool":false},{"option":"Iliotibial band","bool":false},{"option":"Iliopsoas","bool":true},{"option":"Biceps femoris","bool":false}]},{"id":49,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"What specific type of knee injury is the Lachman test primarily used for diagnoses?","answers":[{"option":"Medial collateral ligament injury","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior cruciate ligament injury","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral collateral ligament  injury","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior cruciate ligament injury","bool":true},{"option":"Meniscus injury","bool":false}]},{"id":50,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"Which of the following is not a long term complication of osteomyelitis?","answers":[{"option":"Ewing sarcoma","bool":true},{"option":"Ulceration","bool":false},{"option":"Secondary amyloidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Squamous cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Draining sinus tract","bool":false}]},{"id":51,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"Which of the following joints is most frequently and severely involved in rheumatoid arthritis?","answers":[{"option":"Interphalangeal joint","bool":true},{"option":"Elbow","bool":false},{"option":"Greater toe","bool":false},{"option":"Sacroiliac joint","bool":false},{"option":"Knee","bool":false}]},{"id":52,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"Which of the following is not a feature of osteoarthritis?","answers":[{"option":"Eburnation of bone","bool":false},{"option":"Osteophytes at joint margins","bool":false},{"option":"Increased osteoclastic activity","bool":true},{"option":"Atrophy of synovium","bool":false},{"option":"Progressive loss of cartilage matrix","bool":false}]},{"id":53,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"Which bursa is affected in clergyman's knee?","answers":[{"option":"Infrapatellar bursa","bool":true},{"option":"Prepatellar bursa","bool":false},{"option":"Pes anserine bursa","bool":false},{"option":"Retropatellar bursa","bool":false},{"option":"Suprapatellar bursa","bool":false}]},{"id":54,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"Simmonds test is used for the diagnosis of which specific tendon rupture?","answers":[{"option":"Peroneal rupture","bool":false},{"option":"Quadriceps rupture","bool":false},{"option":"Achilles tendon rupture","bool":true},{"option":"Tibialis posterior rupture","bool":false},{"option":"Tibialis anterior rupture","bool":false}]},{"id":55,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"A 21-year-old male presents to the clinic with a complaint of pain in his right knee. X-ray indicates an avulsion fracture of the tibial tubercle. Which structure is most likely injured from the following?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior cruciate ligament","bool":false},{"option":"Medial cruciate ligament","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral collateral ligament","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior cruciate ligament","bool":false},{"option":"Meniscus","bool":true}]},{"id":56,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"Which tumor is common in the epiphysis region?","answers":[{"option":"Osteosarcoma","bool":false},{"option":"Ewing sarcoma","bool":false},{"option":"Chondroblastoma","bool":false},{"option":"Giant cell tumor","bool":true},{"option":"Lymphoma","bool":false}]},{"id":57,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"Which of the following factors makes aspirin different from other non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drugs (NSAIDs)?","answers":[{"option":"Decreases fever","bool":false},{"option":"Selectively inhibits cycloxygenase-2 enzyme","bool":false},{"option":"Prevents episodes of gouty arthritis with long term use","bool":false},{"option":"Increases the risk of colon cancer","bool":false},{"option":"Irreversibly inhibits cycloxygenase","bool":true}]},{"id":58,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"Which of the following is an analgesic and anti-pyretic drug that lacks an anti-inflammatory action?","answers":[{"option":"Probenecid","bool":false},{"option":"Acetaminophen","bool":true},{"option":"Colchicine","bool":false},{"option":"Indomethacin","bool":false},{"option":"Celecoxib","bool":false}]},{"id":59,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"A 28-year-old male presents to the emergency department with a history of falling on his outstretched hand in a road traffic accident. On examination, there is pain and tenderness in his right forearm, the distal nerve is intact. X-ray shows a distal radius fracture with dislocation of the ulna. What term is used to describe the fracture in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Galeazzi fracture","bool":true},{"option":"Monteggia fracture","bool":false},{"option":"Smith fracture","bool":false},{"option":"Complex distil radius fracture","bool":false},{"option":"Colles fracture","bool":false}]},{"id":60,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"Which of the following imaging modalities is most commonly used to assess joint damage in arthritis?","answers":[{"option":"Computed tomography (CT)","bool":false},{"option":"Ultrasound","bool":false},{"option":"Positron emission tomography (PET)","bool":false},{"option":"X-ray","bool":true},{"option":"Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI)","bool":false}]},{"id":61,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"Which of the following is the main advantage of ketorolac over aspirin?","answers":[{"option":"It can be injected intramuscularly/intravenously","bool":true},{"option":"It does not prolong the bleeding time","bool":false},{"option":"It can be given with opiods more safely such as codeine","bool":false},{"option":"It is less likely to cause acute renal failure in pre-existing renal impairment","bool":false},{"option":"It can be obtained as an over the counter medication","bool":false}]},{"id":62,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"An 18-month-old boy dies from an accidental overdose of acetaminophen. Which of the following is the most likely cause of this patient's death?","answers":[{"option":"Severe anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary edema","bool":false},{"option":"Hemorrhagic stroke","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory failure","bool":false},{"option":"Liver failure","bool":true}]},{"id":63,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"A 55-year-old woman has been diagnosed as a case of acute gout and the physician is prescribing her a high dose of colchicine. The high dose of colchicine is more likely to cause which of the following side effects?","answers":[{"option":"Severe diarrhea","bool":true},{"option":"Skin rash","bool":false},{"option":"Behavioral changes including psychosis","bool":false},{"option":"Diabetes mellitus","bool":false},{"option":"Hypertension","bool":false}]},{"id":64,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"Which of the following is an IL-6 receptor antagonist that is also found to be effective in treating rheumatoid arthritis?","answers":[{"option":"Tocilizumab","bool":true},{"option":"Abatacept","bool":false},{"option":"Leflunomide","bool":false},{"option":"Anakinra","bool":false},{"option":"Rituximab","bool":false}]},{"id":65,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"A 45-year-old woman presents to the rheumatology clinic with a six-month history of stiff hands and wrists. She mentions that the pain is particularly bad in the morning. On examination, the wrist, metacarpophalangeal joints, and proximal interphalangeal joints are swollen and warm. A diagnosis of rheumatoid arthritis is suspected. The physician prescribes methotrexate along with a TNF-alpha inhibitor. Which of the following drugs belongs to TNF-alpha inhibitors?","answers":[{"option":"Sulfasalazine","bool":false},{"option":"Anakinra","bool":false},{"option":"Adalimumab","bool":true},{"option":"Rituximab","bool":false},{"option":"Leflunomide","bool":false}]},{"id":66,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"Which of the following is a disease modifying antirheumatic drug whose active metabolite inhibits the enzyme dihydroorotate dehydrogenase?","answers":[{"option":"Colchicine","bool":false},{"option":"Leflunomide","bool":true},{"option":"Nimesulide","bool":false},{"option":"Sulfasalazine","bool":false},{"option":"Methotrexate","bool":false}]},{"id":67,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"Which of the following drugs is used for the treatment of rheumatoid arthritis with special precautions to guard against the development of irreversible retinopathy?","answers":[{"option":"Infliximab","bool":false},{"option":"Hydroxychloroquine","bool":true},{"option":"Methotrexate","bool":false},{"option":"Sulfasalazine","bool":false},{"option":"Celecoxib","bool":false}]},{"id":68,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"A 59-year-old female is referred to the clinic for evaluation of osteopenia. Since menopause at 52 years of age, she has been on daily vitamin D supplementation. Her bone mineral density test reveals a T score of -1.6 at the lumbar spine, -2.2 at the left femoral neck, and -1.6 at the total left hip. Vitamin D acts through a nuclear receptor to produce which of the following effects in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Increases parathyroid hormone formation","bool":false},{"option":"Increases the renal production of erythropoietin","bool":false},{"option":"Lowers the serum phosphate concentration","bool":false},{"option":"Increases the absorption of calcium from the gastrointestinal tract","bool":true},{"option":"Decreases the absorption of calcium from bone","bool":false}]},{"id":69,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"A male patient of 60 years of age was diagnosed with a case of chronic gout. The treating physician prescribed him allopurinol for his treatment. Which of the following statements best describes the mechanism of action of allopurinol?","answers":[{"option":"It inhibits acetyl transferase","bool":false},{"option":"It inhibits acetylcholinesterase","bool":false},{"option":"It inhibits xanthine oxidase","bool":true},{"option":"It inhibits DNA gyrase","bool":false},{"option":"It inhibits dihydrofolate reductase","bool":false}]},{"id":70,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"Which of the followings drugs is not included in disease modifying anti-rheumatic drugs (DMARDs) therapy?","answers":[{"option":"Sulfasalazine","bool":false},{"option":"Corticosteroids","bool":true},{"option":"Methotrexate","bool":false},{"option":"Leflunomide","bool":false},{"option":"Hydroxychloroquine","bool":false}]},{"id":71,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"Which of the following is the most common skeletal dysplasia?","answers":[{"option":"Achondroplasia","bool":true},{"option":"Neurofibromatosis","bool":false},{"option":"Thanatophoric dysplasia","bool":false},{"option":"Fibrous dysplasia","bool":false},{"option":"Spondyloepiphyseal dysplasia","bool":false}]},{"id":72,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"“Brittle bone disease” is a name given to which of the following skeletal dysplasias?","answers":[{"option":"Multiple epiphyseal dysplasia","bool":false},{"option":"Achondrogenesis","bool":false},{"option":"Spondyloepiphyseal dysplasia","bool":false},{"option":"Stippled epiphysis","bool":false},{"option":"Osteogenesis imperfecta","bool":true}]},{"id":73,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"An 18-month-old boy is brought to the outpatient department (OPD) with a complaint of inability to walk. He has a poor dietary history with a diet mainly comprising buffalo milk and solids. On examination, the child has a 10kg (22lb) weight, 80cm (2.6ft) height, and is found to be irritable. His anterior fontanelle is wide open and a prominent widening of the distal ends of his wrist is also seen. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Scurvy","bool":false},{"option":"Mucopolysaccharidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Achondroplasia","bool":false},{"option":"Epiphyseal dysplasia","bool":false},{"option":"Rickets","bool":true}]},{"id":74,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"A 3-year-old boy is brought to the outpatient department (OPD) for the assessment of difficulty in walking. According to the patient’s mother, he started walking at 15 months of age but has been facing difficulty in climbing stairs for the last 6 months. On examination, muscle bulk in the legs is reduced bilaterally and calf muscles are hypertrophied. Tone, power, and reflexes are found to be normal but the boy has a waddling gait. Lab findings indicate markedly raised serum creatine kinase levels. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Duchenne muscular dystrophy","bool":true},{"option":"Rickets","bool":false},{"option":"Myotonic muscular dystrophy","bool":false},{"option":"Becker muscular dystrophy","bool":false},{"option":"Spinal muscular dystrophy","bool":false}]},{"id":75,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"An 11-year-old girl presents to the clinic with right knee pain for 10 months with no history of trauma. Pain is not limiting her activities. On examination, she is found to be obese. Her right knee appears normal with no tenderness on hip joints. A pelvis radiograph of both hips shows a widening of the proximal femoral epiphyseal growth plate. What is the most likely diagnosis for this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Achondroplasia","bool":false},{"option":"Osteogenesis imperfecta","bool":false},{"option":"Legg-Calve-Perthes disease","bool":false},{"option":"Septic arthritis","bool":false},{"option":"Slipped capital femoral epiphysis","bool":true}]},{"id":76,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"A 7-year-old boy presents with worsening pain in his leg for about four months. His right foot has started to turn inwards while walking resulting in a noticeable limp. A plain radiograph of the hip joint shows a flattened femoral head. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Septic arthritis","bool":false},{"option":"Slipped capital femoral epiphysis","bool":false},{"option":"Legg-Calve-Perthes disease","bool":true},{"option":"Achondroplasia","bool":false},{"option":"Osteogenesis imperfecta","bool":false}]},{"id":77,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"Which of the following is the best practical solution to remove temporary hardness of water at home?","answers":[{"option":"Ion exchange method","bool":false},{"option":"Chlorination","bool":false},{"option":"Boiling","bool":true},{"option":"Addition of lime","bool":false},{"option":"Addition of caustic soda","bool":false}]},{"id":78,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"Which one of the following statements is the most appropriate regarding the biological oxygen demand?","answers":[{"option":"It shows growth and oxygen demand of bacteria","bool":true},{"option":"It shows the amount of oxygen available for life to survive in water","bool":false},{"option":"It is the indicator of acidity","bool":false},{"option":"It is the sum of polyvalent cations","bool":false},{"option":"It is the indicator of dissolved oxygen","bool":false}]},{"id":79,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"A community in a small village in Northern Sindh seeks advice from a public health officer regarding the best source of water to avoid arsenic poisoning. Which one of the following sources of water must be advised against since it is most likely to be polluted with high levels of arsenic?","answers":[{"option":"Rain water","bool":false},{"option":"Surface water","bool":false},{"option":"Ground water","bool":true},{"option":"Lake water","bool":false},{"option":"Spring water","bool":false}]},{"id":80,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"Which of the following is the most important component of a slow sand filter that is subjected to many purification processes?","answers":[{"option":"An under drainage system","bool":false},{"option":"Permutit medium","bool":false},{"option":"Filter control valves","bool":false},{"option":"Supernatant water","bool":false},{"option":"A bed of graded sand","bool":true}]},{"id":81,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"Which one of the following is the most cost-effective workable source of water for the Thar desert region that is least likely to be contaminated by pathogens along with being less likely to dry up during the prolonged summer season in the region?","answers":[{"option":"Construction of a desalination plant","bool":false},{"option":"Digging a shallow well","bool":false},{"option":"Digging a deep well","bool":true},{"option":"Building a tube well","bool":false},{"option":"Storage of rain water","bool":false}]},{"id":82,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"A 44-year-old man visits a physician with complaints of chronic productive cough. He has also developed dyspnea on mild exertion lately. Chest X-ray shows small irregular opacities most prominent in the upper poles of the lungs. The man has a history of working in coal mines for 5 years. Which of the following is the most likely disease the physician should suspect?","answers":[{"option":"Anthracosis","bool":true},{"option":"Byssinosis","bool":false},{"option":"Silicosis","bool":false},{"option":"Bagassosis","bool":false},{"option":"Asbestosis","bool":false}]},{"id":83,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"The use of marble and stones gives an artistic look to the buildings. However, the workers of stone cutting, sandblasting, and ceramic industry are likely to be predisposed to which one of the following diseases?","answers":[{"option":"Bagassosis","bool":false},{"option":"Anthracosis","bool":false},{"option":"Asbestosis","bool":false},{"option":"Silicosis","bool":true},{"option":"Byssinosis","bool":false}]},{"id":84,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"People living in cities are continuously exposed to the adverse effects of noise. Which of the following is the most important source of noise pollution in urban areas?","answers":[{"option":"Industries","bool":false},{"option":"Bulldozers","bool":false},{"option":"Electrical generators","bool":false},{"option":"Transport","bool":true},{"option":"Construction of buildings","bool":false}]},{"id":85,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"An industrial worker has been exposed to noise pollution caused by industrial machines for the last 15 years. What is the most common auditory effect of long-term exposure to noise pollution?","answers":[{"option":"Noise-induced hearing loss","bool":true},{"option":"Auditory fatigue","bool":false},{"option":"Sleep disturbance","bool":false},{"option":"Hypertension","bool":false},{"option":"Stress and anxiety","bool":false}]},{"id":86,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"A 20-year-old is sent for dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry to evaluate the bone mineral density of his lumbar spine, femoral neck, and total hip. The test results revealed significantly low bone mineral density in all sites. Which of the following drugs is routinely added to prevent osteomalacia?","answers":[{"option":"Plicamycin","bool":false},{"option":"Gallium nitrate","bool":false},{"option":"Cholecalciferol","bool":true},{"option":"Sevelamer","bool":false},{"option":"Calcitriol","bool":false}]},{"id":87,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"A 40-year-old male is diagnosed with gout based on the synovial fluid analysis of his knee joint. Which of the following is an indication to start urate-lowering therapy?","answers":[{"option":"Evidence of bone or joint damage","bool":true},{"option":"Serum uric acid of 5.6 mg/dl","bool":false},{"option":"Increased WBC count on CBC","bool":false},{"option":"Raised erythrocyte sedimentation rate (ESR)","bool":false},{"option":"Raised C-reactive protein (CRP)","bool":false}]},{"id":88,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"The arc welding affects the eyes causing intense conjunctivitis and keratitis. Welder’s flash is caused by increased exposure to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Ionizing radiation","bool":false},{"option":"Ultraviolet radiation","bool":true},{"option":"Radioactive isotopes","bool":false},{"option":"Ultrasound","bool":false},{"option":"X-rays","bool":false}]},{"id":89,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"Which one of the following diseases is caused by exposure to ionizing radiations, x-rays, and radioactive isotopes?","answers":[{"option":"Anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Polycythemia","bool":false},{"option":"Bulimia","bool":false},{"option":"Insomnia","bool":false},{"option":"Leukemia","bool":true}]},{"id":90,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"A 50-year-old obese male presents to the clinic with complaints of pain and swelling in the first metatarsophalangeal joint of the left big toe for 2 days. He has a history of alcohol intake for 10 years. The given explanation best corresponds to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Involvement of big toe","bool":false},{"option":"Presence of monosodium urate crystals in synovial fluid","bool":true},{"option":"History of alcohol intake","bool":false},{"option":"Presence of tophi","bool":false},{"option":"Serum uric acid level 8mg/dl","bool":false}]},{"id":91,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"A 10-year-old boy is brought to the clinic for assessment of short stature. He is the shortest in his class, good at studies, and also takes part in sports activities. On examination, the child is vitally stable, prepubertal having a height of 110 cm (3.6 ft), a weight of 27 kg (59.5 lb) with bone age of 10 years. His two elder siblings and father also have a short height. What is the most likely cause of his short stature?","answers":[{"option":"Familial short stature","bool":true},{"option":"Achondroplasia","bool":false},{"option":"Constitutional short stature","bool":false},{"option":"Spondyloarthropathy","bool":false},{"option":"Hypothyroidism","bool":false}]},{"id":92,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"A 28-year-old female is found to have deep vein thrombosis. She also has a history of two miscarriages. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Inflammatory myositis","bool":false},{"option":"Rheumatoid arthritis","bool":false},{"option":"Systemic lupus erythematosus","bool":false},{"option":"Sjogren syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Antiphospholipid antibody syndrome","bool":true}]},{"id":93,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"A 3-year-old boy is brought to the outpatient department (OPD) for growth assessment. On examination, he is vitally stable with a height of 85 cm (2.7 ft) and a weight of 12 kg (26 lbs). The child also has frontal and parietal bossing, bowed legs, and prominent costochondral junctions. His serum calcium is found to be 10 mg/dl, alkaline phosphatase is 520 IU/L and serum vitamin D is 4 ng/ml. Which of the following is the most appropriate treatment choice?","answers":[{"option":"Calcium 500 mg once daily for 1 month","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin D 5 drops/day for 1 month","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin D3 100,000 IU IM STAT","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin D3 300,000 IU IM STAT","bool":true},{"option":"Vitamin D3 600,000 IU IM STAT","bool":false}]},{"id":94,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"Which of the following features is not a characteristic of osteopetrosis?","answers":[{"option":"Hypercalcemia","bool":true},{"option":"Parathyroid hormone is unaffected","bool":false},{"option":"Hereditary defect in osteoclast function","bool":false},{"option":"Fracture susceptibility","bool":false},{"option":"Overgrowth of calcified dense bone","bool":false}]},{"id":95,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"Which of the following disease-modifying antirheumatic drugs provides the fastest symptom relief in rheumatoid arthritis?","answers":[{"option":"Auranofin","bool":false},{"option":"Sulfasalazine","bool":false},{"option":"Methotrexate","bool":true},{"option":"Hydroxychloroquine","bool":false},{"option":"Leflunomide","bool":false}]},{"id":96,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"Which of the following is the serum marker that indicates increased osteoclastic activity?","answers":[{"option":"C reactive protein","bool":false},{"option":"Total acid phosphatase level","bool":false},{"option":"Total alkaline phosphatase level","bool":false},{"option":"Bony acid phosphatase level","bool":true},{"option":"Serum alkaline phosphatase level","bool":false}]},{"id":97,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2023","question":"How many days are required for an uncalcified osteoid matrix to be mineralized?","answers":[{"option":"5-8 days","bool":false},{"option":"3-5 days","bool":false},{"option":"27 days","bool":false},{"option":"8-12 days","bool":false},{"option":"12-15 days","bool":true}]}]
export default arr